shop101.com 2017-06-06

# Shop101 - Privacy Policy

### Introduction

**O(1) India Private Limited** , a company registered under the Companies Act, 2013 having its registered office at Office no. 135, Hubtown Solaris, N.S Phadke Marg, Andheri East-West Flyover Junction, Andheri (East), Mumbai operates this platform with brand name Shop101 (hereinafter referred as **“Shop101”** , **“We”** , **“Us”** or **“Our”** ).

We respect the privacy of its users accessing this mobile application/website which provides a collection of online resources, including online stores, classified advertisements, forums, related sites including the mobile application of the platform at [www.shop101.com](https://shop101.com/) and Google Play Store and Apple App Store ( **“Platform”** ). For the purposes of this privacy policy the term “User(s)” and wherever the context so requires “You”, “Your”, “Yourself” shall mean any natural or legal person who accesses or uses the Platform and in the event that a natural person is representing a business entity, reference to such terms shall include a reference to such business entity as well

Shop101 has adopted this privacy policy ( **“Privacy Policy”** ) to inform You of: (i) the information We collect from You through the Platform; (ii) the manner of collection of such information; (iii) Our use of such information; and (iv) the steps We take to protect it. Capitalized terms not defined herein shall have the meaning ascribed to them in the [Merchants’ Agreement](https://shop101.com/static/termsOfService.html#seller) and the [Buyers’ Agreement](https://shop101.com/static/termsOfService.html#buyer). By using the Platform, You unconditionally agree to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy and consent to usage, storage and handling of the information submitted by You in accordance with the terms contained hereunder. If You do not agree with the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy, please do not proceed further to use this Platform.

### User information

Shop101 collects Your Information when You successfully submit information while creating Your account or while confirming Your order on the Platform ( **“User Information”** ). User Information is the data that can be used to uniquely identify or contact a person and/or the business entity that a person represents and shall include, but not be limited to, information regarding Your name, name of the business entity that You represent, address and telephone number of the business entity, Your e-mail address, information associated to Your social networking platform and such other information for the purposes of identification and verification. We do not directly process any payments and do not store your debit/credit card information. Secured socket layer technology is used for processing payment transactions with third party service provider partners. When You submit User Information on the Platform, it shall be deemed that You have granted Us the right to collect, store, process, handle and use such User Information, in accordance with this Privacy Policy (as amended from time to time).

You may visit the Platform and browse the Platform without having to provide User Information. Where possible, We indicate which fields are mandatory and which fields are optional to be filled on the Platform. You always have the option to not provide information by choosing not to submit particular information or feature on the Platform. When you visit the Platform, we may collect certain non-personal information such as your internet protocol address, operating system, browser type, and internet service provider. This type of information does not identify you personally during Your visit to the Platform. We can identify You only after You submit User Information at the time of registering Yourself with the Platform.

By using this Platform, You consent to the collection, storage, and use of the User Information that you provide for any of the services that We offer, and You consent to our collection of any changes or updates that you may provide to the User Information. Shop101 collects only such User Information that Shop101 believes to be relevant for the purpose of identification and verification and is required to understand You or Your interests. It is clarified that We shall not be liable, for any reason whatsoever, for the authenticity of any User Information provided by You to Us. You hereby confirm that the User Information provided by You is and shall continue to be valid, true and accurate to the best of Your knowledge.

### Collection of information

To enhance Your use of the Platform, certain information may be collected each time You visit the Platform which are saved in server logs. It is clarified that these statistics help Us in improving the efficiency of the Platform by giving Us information relating to Your use of the Platform. Such information may include details of the server from where the Platform is being accessed, the browser and operating system used to browse the Platform, details of Your last visit to the Platform, including time, date and the duration of Your session on the Platform. This information is used by Shop101 to understand the number of users visiting the Platform and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use of the Platform. While collecting such information, Your anonymity is maintained at all times and at no time can We identity You personally, unless You submit the User Information on the Platform or through the e-mail feature. Shop101 reserves the right to share such general information to any person on its discretion.

You acknowledge that apart from Your User Information, if You upload or exchange any data, content, information, pictorial representations and/or images (“Content”) including comments on the Platform, such Content may contain information including User Information and the same may be available to the other Users of the Platform. Shop101 will not be liable for the disclosure and dissemination of such User Information on the Platform.

### Cookies

Like most other Platforms, We use data collection devices known as cookies to collect and store information of Users visiting the Platform. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to a User's browser from a web server/mobile application and is eventually stored on a User's computer hard drive/mobile device. Cookies are a reliable mechanism for Platforms to remember the activities of the User on the Platform and helps in improving Your experience on the Platform. This anonymous information is maintained distinctly and is not linked to the User Information You submit to Shop101. The option of accepting cookies is up to You, however certain features of the Platform including Content and the forms may not be accessible without accepting cookies.

To browse anonymously, You may set your browser to disable cookies or delete cookies. Most cookies are session cookies that are automatically deleted from Your hard drive when You close the browser. Additionally, You may encounter cookies or other similar devices on certain pages of the Platform that are placed by third parties. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties and shall not be liable for any reason whatsoever for these third party cookies.

### User Information

User Information provided by You is used by Us for the following:

  * verifying Your identity;
  * facilitating Your use of the Platform;
  * facilitating successful purchase of Products from the Platform;
  * responding to Your queries or complaints or to fulfil Your requests for information about the services and solutions that We offer and the process relating to the same;
  * providing You with information about Shop101and to send You information, materials, and offers from Shop101;
  * sending You important information regarding the Platform;
  * sending You surveys and marketing communications that Shop101 believes may be of interest to You;
  * personalizing Your experience on the Platform by presenting offers tailored to You;
  * helping You address trouble- shooting problems;
  * providing You with related customer service;
  * conducting internal reviews and data analysis for the Platform (e.g., to determine the number of visitors to specific pages within the Platform);
  * sharing such information with third parties that We consider may have goods or services that are of interest to You;
  * improving the Content on the Platform;
  * protecting the integrity of the Platform; and
  * to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law.

### Sharing of User Information

User Information may be shared with such third parties as are required for: (a) the purposes of providing You with the services on the Platform, and may be subject to the practices of such third parties; or (b) facilitating the purchase of the Products on the Platform by You, to grow Our business which may include our affiliates, strategic partners, investors, suppliers, and service providers as the case maybe. The User Information may be saved in servers, at Our sole discretion.

Except as provided in paragraph above, We shall disclose the User Information only in circumstances where:

  * The User has provided express instructions or consent towards such disclosure;
  * We in good faith believe that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental or regulatory request; (b) enforce the applicable User Agreement or Privacy Policy; (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Shop101, its Users or the public as required or permitted by law; and
  * If we sell or transfer any of our business or assets, certain User Information may be a part of that sale or transfer. In the event of such a sale or transfer, we will notify you.

### Security Precautions

To prevent any form of unlawful interception or misuse of User Information, We use reasonable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the User Information collected. We use reasonable secure and technologically appropriate measures, in compliance with the Information Technology Act, 2000 and the rules related thereto to protect You against loss or misuse of Your User Information including internal reviews of data collection, storage and processing practices and other reasonable security measures which are equivalent to security measures that Shop101 uses to protect its own confidential information. We have in place a secure server for all Your transactions on the Platform, which, if required to be accessed, are accessible only by the authorized personnel of Shop101. However as You are aware, no internet site/mobile based application is completely free of security risks and We do not make any representation in respect of the same.

We do not warrant that Our Platform or any electronic communication made by Us is free from virus or other harmful effects. In the event of any errors in transmission or due to an act of a third party, We shall have no liability. You explicitly agree that Your use of the Platform and/or services is at Your own individual risk. You agree and confirm that Your User Information may be transferred, processed and stored. You hereby confirm that You have been made aware of the security measures undertaken by Us and You expressly consent to Us storing, handling, using Your User Information.

### Links to other third party sites

The Platform may provide third party information and links to other platforms that are not affiliates of or operated or controlled by Shop101 including but not limited to payment gateways or social networking platforms. Shop101 is not responsible for any form of transmission, whatsoever, received by You from any third party platform and accordingly does not make any representations concerning the privacy practices or other policies of such third party Platforms. Under no circumstances shall Shop101 be deemed to control or guarantee the accuracy, integrity, or quality of the information, data, text, software, sound, photographs, graphics, videos, cookies, messages or other materials available on such platforms. Any User Information provided by You to such third party Platforms shall be governed in accordance with the privacy policies of such platforms and it is recommended that You review the privacy policy of such platforms prior to using such platforms.

### Change in Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to update, modify and amend any of the terms of Our Privacy Policy, at any time without prior intimation to You. We will post these changes on Our Platform for Your information. These changes will become effective immediately on posting. We shall not be liable for any failure or negligence on Your part to review the updated Privacy Policy before accessing or availing the Platform for availing the services. Your continued use of the Platform, following changes to the Privacy Policy, will constitute Your acceptance of those changes.

### Intellectual Property rights

All Content on Our Platform, including graphics, text, icons, interfaces, audio clips, logos, images, reviews, comments and software is the property of Shop101 and/or its Content suppliers and is protected by Indian and international copyright laws. Any use, including the reproduction, modification, distribution, transmission, republication, display or performance, of the Content on this Platform can only be made with the express permission of Shop101. All other trademarks, brands and copyrights other than those belonging to Shop101, belong to their respective owners and are their property.

### Force Majeure

Notwithstanding anything contained in this Privacy Policy or elsewhere, Shop101 shall not be held responsible for any loss, damage or misuse of Your User Information, if such loss, damage or misuse is attributable to a Force Majeure Event. A "Force Majeure Event" shall mean any event that is beyond the reasonable control of Shop101 and shall include, without limitation, sabotage, fire, flood, explosion, acts of God, civil commotion, strikes or industrial action of any kind, riots, insurrection, war, acts of government, computer hacking, technical snags, unauthorized access to computer data and storage device, technical snags and breach of security and encryption.

### Disclosures Required By Law

Shop101 reserves the right to disclose information when required by law. We will disclose such information wherein We have a good-faith belief that it is necessary to comply with a court order, ongoing judicial proceeding, or other legal process served on Us or to exercise Our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

### Contacting the Platform

If You have any questions about (i) this Privacy Policy; (ii) practices of this Platform, or (iii) Your dealings with this Platform or believe that We have not adhered to it, You may contact [support@shop101.com](mailto:support@shop101.com)
